why buy the rogue ohio bar for nearly
five hundred dollars
when you can buy its twin for around
three hundred dollars believe it or not
there's actually arguments to be made
for both sides here i'm gonna compare
the two
let's dive in
what is up everyone it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video i've got the rogue ohio bar and
the rogue echo 2.0
in this video i'm going to compare the
two and help you decide which one you
need for your home gym
all right before i get started with any
of that
i got to let you know we have reviewed a
ton of barbells on barbin.com and if you
want to explore our best list just
search barbind best barbells and you can
find out for yourself which ones that we
like the best
[Music]
okay i know i said the echo 2.0 is the
ohio bars twin not identical but they do
share some of the same similarities so
let's start with the tensile strength
which in my opinion is the main factor
in deciding on a barbell so tensile
strength is essentially how much weight
and force a barbell is going to be able
to handle before it begins to bend or
break on you so the echo 2.0 and all of
the options of the ohio bar minus the
stainless steel version we have here
share a tensile strength rating of 190
000 psi
both of these barbells also have a
medium grade knurling which is really
nice for those olympic style and
crossfit style lifts you might find
yourself doing and because both of these
barbells do have bronze bushings in the
sleeves it's going to allow them to spin
which is really ideal for those lifts
sticking with the sleeves they both have
a grooved pattern which is really really
nice in terms of keeping your weight
plates locked in place and it's going to
do it at a much higher rate than a
barbell with smooth sleeves and neither
one of these barbells have a center
knurling that's really nice for those
olympic style lifts because it's not
going to irritate your skin but you're
also going to miss out on the
opportunity of doing a suitcase style
lift or you know maybe you do want that
extra grip while you're doing a cleaning
jerk or when you're squatting it's going
to give you that extra grip if you had
that center knurling
[Music]
okay so what about those differences all
right i did mention the stainless steel
ohio bar does have a higher tensile
strength rating you're going to see this
one jump up to 200 000 psi which really
makes it more accommodating for those
elite level weight lifters the echo 2.0
only comes in a regular zinc finish
while with the ohio bar you have a
couple different options that you can
choose from there's also a pretty big
price difference between the two
so for this video we have the stainless
steel version of the ohio bar it's worth
mentioning there is not a regular zinc
finish like you find in the echo 2.0
so with the stainless steel ohio
you're looking at around 370 bucks
the sleeves are chrome but you can also
get them stainless steel that's going to
be an extra 95 or so
and with shipping you're looking at
spending upwards of 500
on your purchase
with the echo 2.0 it's priced around
270.
all you have is that extra 25 bucks in
shipping so you're looking right around
if you're interested in the other
options of the rogue ohio bar
the black zinc and the eco are both
listed around 300
the black oxide is around 320 and that
custom bar that you can literally
customize almost every aspect of the bar
that's about 350 bucks now in my opinion
if you're gonna go down the route of
getting the ohio bar you might as well
just go with that stainless steel
because you're gonna get that extra
protection from rust and corrosion
[Music]
okay so the version of the ohio bar that
we have is stainless steel with chrome
sleeves this is going to really fight
off rust and corrosion at a much higher
rate than the zinc on the echo 2.0 this
is probably the main reason for the
price difference in my opinion second
one off the top of my head has to be the
warranty so with the ohio you're getting
a lifetime warranty here with the echo
2.0 you're only getting a one-year
warranty so this is something you've
really got to consider
especially for those people who are
putting their barbell through the ringer
in the gym
okay so let's dig into the build now
that went into both of these barbells
they're both very high quality but they
also use different materials this is the
stainless steel version of the ohio bar
this is a zinc finish on the echo 2.0
this stainless steel bar is going to
fight off rust and corrosion much better
than the echo 2.0 can the stainless
steel version of the ohio does have a
tensile strength rating of 200 000 psi
while the other options that tensile
strength rating is 190 000 psi which is
similar to the echo 2.0 both of these
barbells do have bronze bushings that
are going to allow the sleeves to spin
which is really what you're looking for
when it comes to olympic or crossfit
style lifts they both also have a
grooved pattern on the sleeves which is
going to keep those weight plates locked
in while you're doing those lips the
knurling on both of these are on the
moderate side of things really nice it
feels good but they're not going to tear
up your hands in the process
i did notice though because of the
stainless steel you get a better grip
with the ohio bar than you do with the
echo 2.0 this is still really nice it
feels really good in my hands not gonna
lie
but this stainless steel just gets the
job done
[Music]
okay so which of these barbells do you
need to add to your home gym well really
making a decision here is going to boil
down to three different factors first
and foremost is the money now it's no
secret the ohio bar is more expensive
than the echo 2.0 especially if you were
to get the stainless steel version that
we have right here tinsel strength is
also going to be a big factor now these
two are pretty similar the other
versions of the ohio bar are the exact
same rating as the echo 2.0 but the 200
000 tensile strength rating of the
stainless steel ohio bar it's really
really nice it's gonna be able to
withstand more
force in the gym it's gonna also lead to
a higher warranty
so the warranty of the ohio bar is a
lifetime warranty while the echo 2.0 is
only one year warranty
but since both of these barbells do
share a lot of the same traits if you're
on a tight budget i'd suggest going with
the echo 2.0 it's just as versatile and
it's going to allow me to hit the same
style of lifts that i would with the
ohio bar but on a budget price
the zinc finish is not gonna fight off
corrosion as well as a stainless steel
can but with that extra money you're
saving you can always invest in a kit
and you can take that extra care that's
gonna be needed to keep this barbell in
your hands for a long time
now me personally i already know i'm
gonna be a little bit lazy in terms of
that proper upkeep needed on a barbell
that does not have stainless steel so if
it was me i would definitely go with
this stainless steel ohio it does have
that higher tinsel strength rating plus
this stainless steel is really nice for
the garage that we're in and especially
since we're in nashville where it tends
to get really humid outside
[Music]
while the tensile strength rating really
isn't far off between these two barbells
i'm still gonna have to go with the
stainless steel ohio bar
i want that lifetime warranty i love the
fact i don't have to worry so much about
corrosion because of the stainless steel
plus it does have some extra tensile
strength which is a very nice safety
blanket which means i can put this
through that much more than the echo 2.0
now with all that being said echo 2.0 is
still a great option for you to consider
especially if you're not interested in
going for the big dog that is the
stainless steel ohio it's super
versatile it does have the same pencil
strength rating as the other versions of
the ohio but at a discounted price
i just personally cannot pass up this
stainless steel ohio bar it looks good
feels good in my hands plus i do get
that extra layer of protection against
corrosion
thanks for watching y'all i hope this
video helped you learn more about the
similarities and the differences between
these two great barbells and also helped
you find one throw into your home gym in
the process
as always stay tuned for my next video
but in the meantime head over to
barbin.com and you can read more on this
comparison just do a quick google search
type in barbind rogue ohio bar verse
rogue echo bar you can read everything
we talked about here today i'll see
y'all later
[Music]
you